astm.org 2019-12-05

# ASTM International - Privacy Policy

ASTM International ("ASTM") takes your privacy seriously. In this Privacy Policy, we explain how we use any Personal Data we collect about you when you use ASTM's websites.

Topics: 

  * "Personal Data" Defined
  * Our Data Protection and Privacy Principles
  * Types of Personal Data We Collect
  * How We Collect and Use Personal Data
  * Sharing of Personal Data
  * Retention of Personal Dataa
  * Cookies
  * Social Plugins and Social Media Widgets
  * Analytics and Marketing
  * Other Websites
  * Children Under the Age of 13
  * Online Tracking
  * Mergers, Acquisitions, and Other Business Transactions
  * Correcting Personal Data
  * Opting Out of Direct Marketing; Changing Preferences
  * California Privacy Rights
  * Users in the European Union, European Economic Area, and Switzerland
  * Contact Us
  * Changes to Our Privacy Policy

## "Personal Data" Defined

In this Privacy Policy, we define Personal Data" broadly as any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. Personal Data includes your name, address, telephone number, purchase history, and may include your IP address.

* * *

## Our Data Protection and Data Privacy Principles

We have in place what we believe to be appropriate physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard and secure the Personal Data we collect through our websites. We limit access to your payment information to those employees and vendors who need access to process your payments. Payment card information provided to the ASTM Online Shop is protected against unauthorized use by 128-bit encryption and Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) security features.

We routinely review our security measures and refer to industry security standards to keep current with best practices.

* * *

## Types of Personal Data We Collect

The Personal Data we collect about you depends upon how you choose to use our websites. Depending upon your use, we may collect and process usage data, your name and contact information, your username and password, the name of your employer, your payment information, your membership status, records of your orders from our ASTM Online Shop, any information you provide when you fill out online forms or surveys, and your IP address.

* * *

## How We Collect and Use Personal Data

We collect Personal Data when you visit our websites, when you order our products and services through the ASTM Online Shop, when you sign up for ASTM membership, and when you fill out online forms and surveys.

We use your Personal Data to monitor website usage, administer your account, process orders you may make, send you marketing materials that may be of interest to you, and to make our websites more user-friendly.

More specific details about those types of Personal Data we collect and why we process them are provided below:

### Usage Data

We collect information about visitors to our site and how visitors use our site.

We will create log files when you visit our site. The files are used for diagnostics and to monitor product usage. The log files do not record your name, address, phone number, or payment card information. We aggregate information about what pages users access or visit. The log files contain some or all of the following information:

  * The Internet Protocol Address (IP Address) of the machine that accessed our websites
  * The date of the visit
  * The time of the visit
  * The path taken through our websites
  * The browser being used
  * A list of files downloaded or viewed
  * Any errors encountered

### Personal Data You Provide to Us

We collect and process the Personal Data you provide to us when you use our site.

We collect and process Personal Data when you order products and services from the ASTM Online Shop, when you sign up to become an ASTM member, when you provide information in an online survey or form, and when you contact us with questions or comments. This Personal Data may include your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, payment card information, employer information, username, and password.

The Personal Data you provide to us is used in the following ways: to respond to emails you send us; to fulfill your ASTM Online Shop orders; to contact you for an online survey; to send you marketing and promotional materials; to administer your online account; and any other use specified at the time you provide the information to us.

* * *

We will share your Personal Data with our suppliers and vendors as necessary to assist us with order fulfillment, payment processing, web services, data analytics, and marketing. Those suppliers and vendors are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of Personal Data and are bound by this Privacy Policy and any applicable confidentiality agreements.

We may disclose Personal Data if required to do so by law or if we believe that the disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with the law or with legal process; (b) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of the ASTM websites; or (c) protect the personal safety or property of ASTM website users, the public or ASTM and its employees.

* * *

## Retention of Personal Data

Generally, the Personal Data we obtain about you will be retained up to seven years after your last purchase. We will indefinitely maintain a record of your membership with ASTM. You may ask us to delete your Personal Data at any time, and we will do so unless we are required to maintain that information to comply with applicable laws or we still need the information for the purposes for which it was collected and processed.

* * *

## Cookies

A "cookie" is a small text file stored on computers, tablets, mobile phones, and any device used to browse the Internet, capable of storing navigation information for statistical or functional purposes. Some cookies may be used to recognize the user viewing a particular website, make navigation easier, and customize the content. For example, cookies allow us to remember your actions and preferences so that you do not have to re-enter information each time you visit our site or navigate to another page. Cookies also allow us to keep track of items you add to your shopping cart.

There are several types of cookies, including, for example, browser cookies, session cookies, and persistent cookies.

### Cookies We Use

We use different types of cookies on our websites. We use cookies that allow customers and members to remain logged in to our site, that keep track of items in your online shopping cart and user actions, and that recognize your site preferences and user attributes.

### Third-Party Cookies

We work with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Those networks may use cookies and web beacons to collect information about your activities on our site and other sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. These technologies and the information collected may be used to track your activity across multiple devices. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: <http://www.aboutads.info/> (or if located in the European Union, by clicking here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Accepting or Rejecting Cookies

You can set your browser to accept or reject the setting of all or certain cookies, or to request to be notified when a cookie is set. Each browser has specific configuration instructions. However, please be aware that the blocking of cookies may have the effect that you will not be able to use all of our website's functions.

* * *

Our websites include different types of "social plugins" and social media widgets.

These features may collect your IP address and information on which pages you are visiting on our websites, and they may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

If you do not want to be tracked by social media widgets, log out of all social networks you're logged in to before visiting our websites.

* * *

## Analytics and Marketing

### Google Analytics (Functional Cookies)

We use [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html), a web analysis service of Google, Inc., to improve the user experience. Google Analytics helps us determine the number of visitors to our site and helps us understand how users find our site. Google Analytics may record your geographical location, device, Internet browser, operating system, and IP address. We are not provided with information allowing us to link an individual to an IP address. More information about Google Analytics can be found in its [Terms of Service](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and in its [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

If you do not want to be tracked by Google Analytics on our websites, you can opt out [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Google AdWords (Advertising Cookies)

We use Google AdWords Conversion tracking cookies to measure and optimize the performance and user experience related to our ads in Google Search or selected Google Display Network sites. To learn more about Google Ads or to opt out of its use of cookies, visit [Google's Ad Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCgqrHM9VMEIFOvktdtKHsBEI7TAjmXGmctVEOx9HxfJ2rpgEWlp7MvrW5QLKqdepbSYIpYSS4-3gxp4ZSlTcZETBU3BT74yWyWEC5nkJXTbWRP5aVc&hl=en).

### Act-On Software, Inc. (Marketing Services)

We work with Act-On Software Inc. to assist us with marketing. Act-On Software Inc. uses cookies to track browsing. If you would like Act-On Software Inc. to delete Personal Data it may have about you, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@astm.org) and we will direct Act-On to do so. They will respond to a request to remove the data within 30 days.

* * *

## Other Websites

This Privacy Policy only applies to ASTM's websites. Our websites contain multiple links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those websites. When visiting non-ASTM websites, you should read the privacy policies of those sites.

* * *

## Children Under the Age of 13

Our websites are not intended for children. No one under age 13 may provide any personal data on our websites. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under 13. If you are under 13, do not use or provide any information on our websites. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Data from a child under 13, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have information from or about a child under 13, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@astm.org).

* * *

## Online Tracking

ASTM does not respond to "do not track" (DNT) signals.

* * *

## Mergers, Acquisitions, and Other Business Transactions.

ASTM may decide to sell, buy, merge, or otherwise reorganize its business. If that occurs, you will be notified via email or a prominent notice on our website of any ownership change and any changes in the use of your Personal Data. These types of transactions may involve the disclosure of Personal Data to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. We seek appropriate protection for Personal Data in these types of transactions.

* * *

## Correcting Personal Data

If you believe that Personal Data we have about you is incorrect, you can make corrections by logging in to your account to [My ASTM](https://myastm.astm.org/CUSTOMERS/welcome.cgi) or ask us to correct the errors by contacting us at [privacy@astm.org](mailto:privacy@astm.org).

* * *

## Opting Out of Direct Marketing; Changing Preferences

You can simply "opt out" of direct marketing or make other changes to your marketing preferences by contacting us at [privacy@astm.org](mailto:privacy@astm.org) and providing us with your name, address, and account number, and telling us what changes you would like to make. You can also make changes to your marketing preferences [here](https://marketing.astm.org/acton/media/9652/astm-subscription).

* * *

## California Privacy Rights

If you are a resident of the state of California and ASTM has an established business relationship with you, then you have certain privacy rights pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code. You have the right to request the following at any time: (a) information from ASTM free of charge regarding the manner in which ASTM shares certain Personal Data collected through the website with third parties who use that information for direct marketing purposes; and (b) the discontinuation (or opt-out) of ASTM's sharing of the information with those third parties. Please submit any requests ("California Privacy Rights Request") to [privacy@astm.org](mailto:privacy@astm.org) with a subject line of "Your California Privacy Rights."

For each California Privacy Rights Request, please state "Your California Privacy Rights" in the email or letter subject line, and clearly state the following in the body:

  * a. the nature of your request;
  * b. that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights;"
  * c. your name, street address, city, state, zip code, and email address; and
  * d. whether you prefer to receive a response to your request by mail or email.

ASTM is not responsible for a California Privacy Rights Request that is incomplete, incorrectly labeled, or incorrectly sent.

* * *

## Users in the European Union, European Economic Area, and Switzerland

### Data Controller

ASTM is the data controller of the Personal Data you provide on our website.

You may contact us by mail, by email, or by telephone.

By mail:

ASTM International  
PO Box C700  
100 Barr Harbor Drive  
West Conshohocken, PA 19428

By email:

By telephone:

+1.610.832.9585

### Purposes of Processing and Legal Basis for Processing

As explained above, we process Personal Data in various ways depending upon your use of our websites. We process Personal Data on the following bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform a contract when you request services; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing you with our products and services, enhancing our web services, conducting analytics, and delivering relevant advertising.

### Your Rights Regarding Personal Data

  * Access and Confirmation. You have the right to ask us if we process Personal Data about you, and in some circumstances, to obtain a copy of your Personal Data.
  * Deletion and Blocking. Under certain circumstances, you may have the right to have your Personal Data deleted or blocked without undue delay.
  * Direct Marketing. You have the right to object to our processing of Personal Data for direct marketing purposes.
  * Consent. To the extent we are processing Personal Data based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw consent at any time.
  * Data Portability. Under certain circumstances, to the extent we are processing your Personal Data based on consent, or that it is necessary to perform a contract with you, and the processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive the Personal Data in a structured, commonly-used and machine-readable format.

To exercise those rights, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@astm.org).

  * Right to Lodge a Complaint. You have the right to lodge a complaint about our data collection and processing actions with the supervisory authority in your country.

### Transfers

We are headquartered in the United States of America. Personal Data may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States. The European Commission has not determined that the United States ensures an adequate level of protection for Personal Data.

By providing us with Personal Data, you consent to the storage or processing of your Personal Data in the United States and acknowledge that the Personal Data will be subject to the laws of the United States, including the ability of governments, courts or law enforcement or regulatory agencies of the United States to obtain disclosure of your Personal Data.

We will protect the privacy and security of Personal Data according to this Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.

* * *

Should you have any further questions or suggestions regarding the protection of your Personal Data processed in connection with the use of our websites, please contact us at [privacy@astm.org](mailto:privacy@astm.org).

* * *

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We regularly review and revise our Privacy Policy. We make changes to the Privacy Policy available on this page and note that the policy has been updated. If we make material changes to how we treat your Personal Data, we will notify you by email to the primary email address specified in your account and through a notice on our homepage.

### This Privacy Policy was last updated on the 24th of May 2018.

### CONTACT US

This is the website of ASTM International. You may contact us by mail, by email, or by telephone.

By mail:

ASTM  
PO Box C700  
100 Barr Harbor Drive  
West Conshohocken, PA 19428

By email:

By telephone:

+1.610.832.9585
